Guide to the California Asian American Artists Biographical Survey Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Non-California Artists Files, Series 3
  - Hiramoto, Masaji (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "First Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by the Japanese Artists of New York City" at The Civic Club, NY, 1922, and "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927.
  - Hirota, Susumu (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "The Japanese American Artists Group," exhibition at The Riverside Museum, New York, NY, 1947.
  - Honda, Hiroshi (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Horiuchi, Paul (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Active in Washington; photocopied information from book "They Painted From Their Hearts"; San Francisco Art Association exhibitions list; catalog from exhibition.
  - Inokuma, Genichiro (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Active in New York and Japan; NYT obituary.
  - Inouye, Mme. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Inouye, T. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Iwamoto, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Active in Hawaii; resume; photocopied articles.
  - Iwasaki, Kenji (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "The Japanese American Artists Group," exhibition at The Riverside Museum, New York, NY, 1947, and "The Japanese American Artists Group," exhibition at The Riverside Museum, New York, NY, 1947.
  - Kadowaki, Roy (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at the ACA Gallery, NY, 1936; photocopied article.
  - Kajiwara, Takuma (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Photographer and painter active St. Louis, MO; examples of artwork (photo of Emma Goldman); photocopied articles; documentation of work in the Library of Congress.
  - Kan, Diana (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Active in New York; narrative biography.
  - Kato, Kentaro (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927, and in National Gallery of Design, 1920.
  - Kato, Rinnosuke (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Kawamura, Gozo (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "First Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by the Japanese Artists of New York City" at The Civic Club, NY, 1922, and in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927; photocopies from Japanese magazine.
  - Kee, Ling (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Photographer active in Oregon; bibliographic citation.
  - Kitagawa, Tamiji (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Active New York, Mexico and Japan; photocopied articles; documentation of artwork in collection of Nagoya City Art Museum, Japan.
  - Kitamori, Seioh (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927.
  - Koike, Kyo (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Photographer active Washington; articles; writings; excerpts from catalogs; examples of artwork.
  - Kondo, Suiseki (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Painter active in Japan who visits San Francisco and Los Angeles in 1930; photocopied article.
  - Kusanobu, Murray (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at the ACA Gallery, NY, 1936, and in "The Japanese American Artists Group," exhibition at The Riverside Museum, New York, NY, 1947.
  - Long, Chin-san (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Noted Chinese photographer who visited California repeatedly; examples of artwork; photo of artist.
  - Matsudaira, John (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Active in Washington; photocopied information from book "They Painted From Their Hearts"; obituary.
  - Matsura, Frank (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Photographer active in Washington; slides; correspondence; photocopies from publication on artist.
  - Matsushita, I. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Photographer active in Washington; articles.
  - Misaki, Michio (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "First Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by the Japanese Artists of New York City" at The Civic Club, NY, 1922, and in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927.
  - Miyamoto, Kaname (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Morinaga, Y. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Photographer active in Washington; photocopied articles.
  - Moy, Seong (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Printmaker active in New York and Minnesota; Archives of American art interview transcript; examples of artwork; documentation of works in the FAMSF collection.
  - Murata, Mrs. Yukiko (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Nagai, Thomas (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Active in New York; internment camp newspaper citation; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at the ACA Gallery, NY, 1936.
  - Nakagawa, Kikuta (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Active in New York; LA Times Index citation; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at the ACA Gallery, NY, 1936.
  - Nakayama, Mitsu (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Namkung, Johsel (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Photographer active in Washington; photocopies of biographical sources.
  - Nishikawa, Dan T. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Active in Hawaii; photocopy of biographical source.
  - Nomura, H. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Obata, Gyo (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Architect active in St. Louis, MO; photocopied article; example of work.
  - Ochi, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Photographer active in Washington.
  - Ochikubo, Tetsuo (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Active in Hawaii; articles, photocopies of catalog exerpts.
  - Okada, Frank S. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Active in Washington and Oregon; resume; correspondence with artist; slides.
  - Okada, Kenzo (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Okakura, Tenshin (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Active in Boston and Japan as curator, artist; photocopy of biographical source.
  - Onishi, H. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Photographer active in Washington; article.
  - Ossorio, Alfonso (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Active in New York; examples of artwork.
  - Parrott, Alice Kagawa (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Active in Hawaii; documentation of exhibition history.
  - Ryokichi, Miki (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "First Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by the Japanese Artists of New York City" at The Civic Club, NY, 1922.
  - Saito, Ryuko (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Active in New York; documentation of exhibition.
  - Sato, Tadashi (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Active in Hawaii; photocopy of biographical source; exhibition documentation; articles.
  - Sawada, Mme. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Shimizu, Kiyoshi (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927, and in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at the ACA Gallery, NY, 1936.
  - Shimizu, Toshi (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "First Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by the Japanese Artists of New York City" at The Civic Club, NY, 1922, and in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927; examples of artwork.
  - Sunami, Soichi (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Photographer active in New York; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927.
  - Tada, S. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Active in Washington; photographer.
  - Tagawa, Bunji (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Takaezu, Toshiko (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Ceramic artist active in Hawaii and New Jersey; photocopied articles.
  - Tamotsu, Chuzo (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Active in New York and New Mexico; documentation of participation in "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927, and the "The Japanese American Artists Group," exhibition at The Riverside Museum, New York, NY, 1947; information regarding his archives; photocopied articles.
  - Tanaka, Yasushi (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Active in Washington State and Paris; articles; photocopied excerpt from catalog.
  - Teng Hiok Chiu (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Active in Boston; exhibition catalog.
  - T'eng K'uei (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Active in Seattle and China; article.
  - Tera, Tetusen (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ting, Walasse (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Active in New York and Paris; examples of artwork.
  - Tsuchidana, Harry (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Active in Hawaii; resume; FAMSF exhibition information; article.
  - Tsutakawa, George (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Active in Washington; dvd; articles; correspondence with artist's daughter; photocopy of publication; materials related to the exhibition "They Painted from their Hearts," DVD of "George Tsutakawa: An Artistic Pilgrimage," a film produced by the Archives of American Art.
  - Usui, Bumpei (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Active in New York; documentation of participation in "First Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by the Japanese Artists of New York City" at The Civic Club, NY, 1922, "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at The Art Center, NY, 1927, "Exhibition by Japanese Artists in New York" at the ACA Gallery, NY, 1936, and "The Japanese American Artists Group," exhibition at The Riverside Museum, New York, NY, 1947; photocopied article.
  - Wang, Fang-yu (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Active in New York; correspondence with artist's son; photo; excerpt from catalog.
  - Watari, Takeo (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Way, John (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Active in New York; information from artist including resume, articles and examples of artwork; magazine; articles; book.
  - Wei, Francis L. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Active in Illinois and California; correspondence with artist; bio; photos of artwork.
  - Yajima, Tokusuke (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Yokouchi, Kiyoharu (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Yoshida, Hiroshi (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Active in Boston and Japan; articles.
  - Young, John Chin (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Active in Hawaii; articles; exhibition documentation.
- Reference Files, Series 4
  These files predominantly contain materials than have been photocopied and placed in individuals artist files.
  - Pictorialist Photography, Subseries 1
    - Dennis Reed cardfile of Los Angeles Japanese pictorialist photographers (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Photocopies of Los Angeles photo historian Dennis Reed's handwritten artist card files; spreadsheet compiling all data from these cards. (Note: Some info may have subsequently been revised since data's inclusion within this archive.)
    - Japanese Camera Pictorialists of California (club) (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Articles, photocopy of photo of group members, catalog with members' names and translation of names.
    - Other Los Angeles camera groups and exhibitions (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Articles.
    - Camera clubs, San Francisco (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Photocopy of photo of club members; article.
    - Pictorialism general (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Photocopies of two catalogs; photocopied excerpt from book; paper written on Japanese pictorialists.
    - Dennis Reed cardfile of Los Angeles Japanese pictorialist photographers (Box 7, Folder 1)
      CD containing excel spreadsheet.
  - General Photography, Subseries 2
    - Photos in the collection of the California Historical Society (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Two pages of hand written notes about photos in the CHS collection.
    - Photographer spreadsheet, general (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Spreadsheet that includes Dennis Reed's pictorialists list and other photographers.
    - Peter Palmquist's list of studio photographers from With New Eyes exhibition catalog (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Spreadsheet list of studio photographers that appearred in the With New Eyes exhibition catalog.
    - Ching Collection photographs (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Names of photographers in the Ching Collection.
  - Schools, Subseries 3
    - Chouinard faculty and students (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Compiled list of nine faculty members and six students.
    - San Francisco Art Institute Enrollment Records (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Spreadsheets organized by name and by date, plus hand written notes.
    - Otis faculty and students (Box 1, Folder 12)
      1927 and 1928 class photos with some students identified, correspondence with Otis archivist.
    - Theodore Wores student information (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Correspondence and photocopy of original source book.
  - Exhibitions and Exhibition Records, Subseries 4
    - Chinese Art Association (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Photocopies of original records from the de Young Museum, and compiled lists of participating artists.
    - Expressions from Exile catalog (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Photocopy of catalog from 1979 exhibition of internment art.
    - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art-artist who exhibited pre-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      List of artists compiled from museum's cardfile (photocopies of the cards appear in each artist's file).
    - Los Angeles artists and vicinity exhibition records (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Spreadsheet of artists who participated in this annual exhibition.
    - Crocker Kingsley exhibition records (Box 1, Folder 18)
      List of artists who participated in this annual exhibition.
    - Misc. Los Angeles area exhibitions (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Spreadsheet of artists who participated in various annual Los Angeles exhibitions.
    - California State Fair records: 1954-56, 1958-62 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      List of participating artists; some photocopies from catalogs.
    - Exhibitions at FAMSF (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Handwritten notes and compiled typed list created after reviewing Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco (de Young Museum and the California Palace of the Legion of Honor) historic files. Some photocopies of materials.
    - Made in California exhibition, LACMA, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Photocopies of pages from exhibition catalog that list Asian American artists included in the show.
    - Los Angeles County Fair exhibition records (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Spreadsheet of participating artists.
    - New York Japanese artist exhibitions (Box 1, Folder 24)
      List compiled from information in book, Eitaro Ishigaki and Other Japanese Artists in the Pre-WWII United States. Wakayama, Japan: The Museum of Modern Art, 1997.
    - Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Photocopies of pages of catalog that document "Japanese Section" with note to American section.
    - Young America exhibition, Whitney Museum, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Photocopies of relevant pages of catalog. Included artists: Sungwoo Chun, Dale Joe, and Noriko Yamamoto.
    - Golden Gate International Exposition 1939/1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Photocopy of "California Art Today" section of catalog, and notes art exhibited in other areas of the fair.
    - WWII era exhibitions (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Newspaper articles largely related to artists from China exhibiting in the United States.
    - See Gallery (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Citation of LA Times article.
    - Pacific Heritage exhibition 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Photocopy of relevant pages of catalog.
    - Paintings by New York Chinese-Japanese Artists, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Photocopy of small catalog of exhibition (original source Archives of American Art).
    - Boston Japanese Print exhibitions 1935, 1938, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Photocopies of four newspaper articles.
    - Zen and Modern Art 2003/04 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Small brochure from exhibition.
    - California State Fair records: 1963, 1964, 1967, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      List of exhibiting artists with some photocopies from exhibition catalogs.
    - The Living Brush 1997 exhibition (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Photocopy of catalog from exhibition that included C.C. Wang and Tseng Yuho.
    - Contemporary Chinese American Artists, Los Angeles, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Newspaper article documenting exhibition.
    - A Third World Painting, Sculpture Exhibition, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Photocopy of catalog from exhibition.
    - With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History in the West (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Exhibition catalog.
    - Asian Traditions/Modern Expressions (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Card announcing exhibition.
    - On Gold Mountain (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Brochure for exhibition at Autry Museum.
    - Resilient Images: Reflections on Internment (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Brochure for exhibition.
    - Other Sources exhibition, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Excerpted pages from catalog on relevant artists.
    - With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History in the West (Box 7, Folder 3)
      3 audio cassettes related to exhibition, With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History in the West.
    - With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History in the West (Box 7, Folder 4)
      2 audio cassettes related to exhibition, With New Eyes: Toward an Asian American Art History in the West.
  - Newspapers, Magazines, Books, Subseries 5
    - New York Times articles (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Approximately 20 articles.
    - Los Angeles Newspapers: Rafu Shimpo & Kashu Mainichi 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Approximately 50 photocopies of relevant articles from newspapers.
    - Los Angeles Newspapers: Rafu Shimpo & Kashu Mainichi 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Approx. 50 photocopies of relevant articles from newspapers.
    - Shin Sekai (New World) San Francisco Japanese language newspaper (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Original (Japanese) articles and translations ca. 1926, 1927.
    - Internment camp newspapers-Tule Lake, Santa Anita, Jerome, Topaz Rohwer (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Photocopies of articles regarding art, artists.
    - Internment camp newspapers-Poston, Manzanar, Granada, Gila River, Heart Mountain (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Photocopies of articles regarding art, artists; and spreadsheet index of articles.
    - Chinese Digest (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Photocopies of articles from the Chinese Digest.
    - San Francisco Chronicle (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Six articles from newspaper.
    - Artists on the Left book (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Photocopied excerpt from book artists include Eitaro Ishigaki, Chuzo Tamotzu, Hideo Noda, Yasuo Kuniyoshi.
    - Nichi Bei Times (The Japanese American News) San Francisco paper (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Email reports from researcher who reviewed ca. 1920s Nichi Bei Times newspaper.
    - Fortune magazine (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Photocopies of pages that include illustrations by Mine Okubo, Dong Kingman, Taro Yashima, and Yasuo Kuniyoshi.
    - Turning Shadows into Light book (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Some photocopied pages from this publication.
    - Japanese Artists Who Studied in U.S.A. and the American Scene book (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Some photocopied pages from this Japanese publication.
    - Japanese and Japanese American Painters in the United States: A Half Century of Hope and Sufferingbook excerpts translated (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Typed translation of chronology and some artists' bios from this Japanese book.
    - Art Digest (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Two photocopied articles.
    - Overland Monthly, ca. 1900 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Illustration of Yone Noguchi by M. Takahashi.
    - East West (newspaper) (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Photocopies of articles.
    - Hindustan Gadar (newspaper) (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Photocopies of articles and illustrations.
    - Parnassus journal (1935) Japanese Painters in America article (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Photocopy of article.
    - California Arts and Architecture magazine Oct. 1939 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Photocopy of issue.
    - The Argus (San Francisco art journal), ca. 1920s (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Los Angeles Times Index (1930-1945) (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Photocopies from Nancy Dustin Wall Moures's publications on Southern Cal Art vols. 4,5,6.
    - Time magazine article, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Review of exhibitions in New York.
    - Boston newspaper articles (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Four articles.
    - Chinese World (newspaper) (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Photocopies of art articles and typed notes.
    - Los Angeles Times articles (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Nine articles.
    - General info, Japanese American newspapers (Box 3, Folder 17)
      List of historic newspapers.
    - Article "Japanese Artists in New York Between the World Wars" Mitsutoshi Oba (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Article downloaded from web.
    - Artists in California, 1786-1940 by Edan Milton Hughes 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Info on pertinent artist from this book, continued in next file.
    - Artists in California, 1786-1940 by Edan Milton Hughes 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Info on pertinent artist from this book, continued from previous file.
  - Internment, Subseries 6
    - Relocation Centers Census Records (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Photocopies of original records, spreadsheet of pertinent info.
    - Relocation Camp Departures Index (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Spreadsheet of data.
    - "Art and the Americas" article (1943) art in internment camps (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - WWII/Internment chronology (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Info on camps and timeline.
    - Collections guide to internment related resources (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Collections guide obtained from web.
    - New Jersey College for Women, internment exhibition 1945 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Several articles regarding this exhibition.
    - Friends Center exhibition, Cambridge, MA (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - All Aboard Topaz camp magazine (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Photocopy of spring 1944 issue.
    - Trek magazine Topaz Camp magazine (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Photocopies of covers and some inside content.
    - Beauty Behind Barbed Wire book (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Photocopies of relevant info.
    - Art Students League, Heart Mountain (Box 3, Folder 31)
      One camp newspaper article.
    - Exhibition at WRA regional office in Denver (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Artists Clubs, Subseries 7
    - Chinese Art Association (San Francisco) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      See Chinese Art Association file in Exhibitions and Exhibition Records.
    - Artists Clubs and Exhibitions in Los Angeles Before 1930 (book) (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Photocopies from Nancy Dustin Wall Moure's book.
    - Shaku-do-sha (Los Angeles club) (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Photocopy of 1923 catalog, photocopies of newspaper articles.
    - Los Angeles area Japanese art clubs (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Misc. references to other clubs.
    - East West Art Society (San Francisco) (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Photocopy of 1922 catalog, correspondence from Matsusaburo Hibi and Chiura Obata.
    - Sangenshoku Ga Kai (San Francisco club) (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Newspaper references; articles.
    - Chinese Revolutionary Artists Club (San Francisco) (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Notes.
    - Chinese Art Club (New York) (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Newspaper articles.
    - California Water Color Society (Nancy Dustin Wall Moure publication) (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Photocopies from Nancy Dustin Wall Moure's book, and spreadsheet of data.
    - Other New York clubs/groups (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Collections, Subseries 8
    - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Printout from their collections; database of relevant artists.
    - Smithsonian American Art Museum (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - San Francisco General Hospital collection (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Photocopy of 1978 publication documenting collection.
    - Security Pacific collection (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Photocopy of ca. 1980s publication documenting collection.
    - Center for Creative Photography collection (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Photocopy of ca. 2003 publication documenting collection.
    - WPA collection, de Young Museum (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Notes regarding artwork in collection.
    - Oakland Museum (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Photocopied list documenting collection.